

Tollan Sitotaw Berhanu

- Male
- 21 Sep 2000
- Not Married
- Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- Ethiopian
- 2nd Grade Auto

- (+251)929111231
- ĭ tollanberhanu@gmail.com
- github.com/TollanBerhanu
- in linkedin.com/in/tollan-sitotawb135b1242
- k tollanberhanu.github.io

About Me

A recent graduate from Jimma University with a degree in Software Engineering (3.97 CGPA). Graduated with high honors and was awarded a Gold Medal for having the highest grade from the faculty. Possess strong leadership and teamwork abilities having been in charge of all class projects throughout my academic career. Experienced in working both independently and in teams to develop various software projects. Interested in artificial intelligence and have a strong desire to advance in that field.

Education

2019 - 2022 **BSc Software Engineering**

Jimma, Ethiopia Jimma Uiversity 3.97 CGPA

Graduated with high honors and received a Gold Medal award for having the

highest CGPA from the Faculty of Computing and Informatics.

2015 - 2018 **High School Diploma** Dandii Boru School

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Was a top-ranking student and an active participant in extracurricular activities. Have been a member of Science and Technology and Red Cross clubs.

Professional Experience

Apr 2022 - Aug 2022 Jimma, Ethiopia

Internship

Jimma University ICT Center

Developed an interactive 'Student Information System' along with a team using

the Laravel framework.

Jun 2019 – Feb 2022 Jimma, Ethiopia

Community Based Training Program

Jimma University

Took part in a three-year program where we engaged with the community to identify its issues and address them using our expertise. We selected Aba Buna Secondary School, for which we created a full-scale 'School Administration

System'.

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 Addis Ababa, Ethiopia Internship

Oromia Science Technology and Information Communication Authority (OSTICA) Developed a 'Kebele Identification Card Preparation System' for Bossa Kitto Kebele using HTML, CSS, JS and PHP. Also developed an interactive company

website for the organization (OSTICA) using Angular JS.

Tollan Sitotaw Berhanu I/2

Certificates

Certificate of Completion - Cisco Networking Academy (For successfully completing all courses in a 210-hour Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNAv7) training program at Jimma University's Cisco Networking Academy.)

Certificate of Appreciation - Mathewos Wondu Ethiopian Cancer Society (For having valuable voluntary contributions to the care, support, and health education of cancer patients and participation in the "Golden September" pediatric cancer awareness creation campaign.)

Awards

Gold Medal Aug 2022

Jimma University, Jimma Institute of technology, Faculty of Computing and Informatics

Awarded a Gold Medal and a Certificate of Recognition for achieving the highest CGPA with very great distinction among the class of 2022 graduates of the Faculty of Computing and Informatics, Jimma Institute of Technology,

Jimma University.

Best Final Year Research Project Aug 2022

Jimma University, Jimma Institute of technology, Faculty of Computing and Informatics

Received a Certificate of Recognition for developing an exceeding final-year research project entitled "University Exam Scoring System using Optical Character Recognition (OCR)" selected as the best project from the Faculty of Computing and Informatics, Jimma Institute of Technology, Jimma University.

Skills

Programming Languages

HTML, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, PHP,

Python, C++, Java

Frameworks

Angular Js, Node Js, Electron Js,

Laravel, Bootstrap

Soft Skills

Leadership | Teamwork | Problemsolving | Communication | Time

Management

DevOps

Git, Google Cloud Services, Insomnia

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB

Canguages

English (Fluent) • Amharic (Native) • Afan Oromo (Fluent)

References

Negassa Berhanu (PhD), Internship Coordinator, Jimma University negasa.fite@ju.edu.et, (+251)472115943

Alemisa Endebu (MSc), Software Engineering Coordinator / Lecturer, Jimma University alemisa2010@gmail.com, (+251)912878635

Zerihun Olana (MSc), Information Technology Coordinator / Lecturer, Jimma University zerihun.olana@ju.edu.et, (+251)912455376

Tollan Sitotaw Berhanu 2/2